Unidentified Belter ships,
you are entering restricted space.
Veer off now, or we will fire!
Barbapiccola, this is the UNN Tripoli.
Shut down your drive now,
or we will fire.
Respond immediately.
We are unarmed.
This is a refugee ship.
Mama, I'm scared.
Whatever happens, we will be together.
Together.
Tripoli,
you are not authorized
to fire inside the Ring Space.
Barbapiccola, the OPA
orders you to comply.
We will not.
We've been begging for a port
since Ganymede fell.
No one would let us land.
If you're going to kill us,
just do it now, or let us go!
Go.
Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Now, that's
a good cup of coffee.
Did you speak to Naomi?
It was lovely meeting her,
except it was through a screen.
It's such a shame she couldn't
come down and see the farm.
Mom...
That was a long trip you were on.
She could have taken those
gravity drugs on the way.
It's not that easy.
Those drugs are brutal.
I wouldn't have asked her
to do that for me.
And this isn't her home.
Most Belters have mixed feelings
about Earth.
Here.
It's for your next long haul.
Think I need to reread this?
What did you see out there?
It's hard to put into words.
Storm's coming.
Mmm.
I'm gonna go close up the house.
I'll be right in.
Gonna be a real turd-floater, huh?
Perfect words for every occasion.
Hey.
We gotta talk about that ride.
The ride? Yeah, I know.
Next clue to the case.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Are we going to the Ring?
We're going to New York.
What the hell's in New York?
Tall buildings, good pizza,
Secretary-General of
the United Nations, who summoned me.
So you can ask her, tell her
to let you go through the Ring.
I have, a hundred times.
I'll bring it up again,
but something must have changed
if she wants to talk.
We gotta talk about that ride, kid.
Next clue to the case.
I wonder what that rain tastes like.
I used to love the rain
when I was a kid.
I'd sit out here and watch
the lightning storms.
Sounds beautiful.
We gotta talk about that ride, kid.
Next clue to the case.
You got it, Miller.
I'll take care of it.
I hope we get a chance
to meet in person one day.
You know, I'm quite a dancer.
Holden never stops saying.
Fong kopenga tolwanda ert el Belte
fong kopenga tolowabda Ert.
Okay, okay, okay.
- Bye, now.
- Bye!
- Bye-bye!
- Bye! Take care!
That was agonizing.
Yes, it was.
I'll see you soon.
Love you.
New railgun's looking good.
I just need you to check out
the thrust compensator.
If this thing's not tied
into our drive just right,
we're all gonna get tossed into
the ceiling every time it fires.
I'm on it.
Hey, Amos.
Melba?
Please, Clarissa.
I get one vid message a month now.
I...
didn't have anyone to call.
- Okay.
- So you coming down the well?
Nope.
Not even to feel the surf
through your toes?
There's a lot of past in my past.
I'm gonna skip it.
At least you have the choice.
I'm gonna spend the rest
of my life in here.
Like Dad.
Yeah, they really
threw the book at you.
I called to say thank you.
For what?
The months heading home,
letting me work in the shop with you,
- it kept me sane.
- You're a good mechanic.
I've been thinking about something.
Remember when you sent me
to check on the...
the seals in the air lock?
Yep.
The safeties
had been overridden, and...
if I wanted to, I could have
blown the outer door
while I was in it, killed myself.
Yep.
Was that on purpose?
If I was staring down
a lifetime sentence,
I'd want to have the option.
It was kind of you to make the offer.
But Anna was right. I...
- I don't deserve the easy way out.
- Stop it.
You breathe in, you breathe out,
eat, shit, sleep,
you take whatever they give you,
and you give nothing in return.
I have to go.
They have me doing dream therapy.
I don't really understand it, but...
the doctor has flowers in her office,
and I can smell them
through the glass.
Good luck with that.
Can I bother you again sometime?
Sure thing, Peaches.
What I want is more ships
at the Ring blockade.
All I need from you
is to make that happen.
Our assets in the outer planets
have been decimated.
We don't have the ships.
We could redeploy
elements of the Home Fleet.
You forgot about Mars?
It's a new day.
We're all friends now.
Madam Secretary, if I may...
Nancy, don't start
this shit with me again.
Half our population is unemployed,
and we've been given
the biggest opportunity
to give them jobs, to give them
a purpose in a century.
Every week, another colony ship
filled with our constituents
shows up at the blockade,
and we make them wait.
They're sitting ducks for pirates.
They want to explore new worlds.
We should let them.
When Columbus arrived,
at least he knew what was
waving at him was human.
We've sent out hundreds
of probes through the Rings.
Not one of them has turned up
any little green men.
You haven't seen it yet,
so it doesn't exist.
That's your argument?
You can't control a goddamn gold rush.
When the stacks of body bags
came back from the Yukon,
thousands of hopeful idiots
lined up to be the next corpses.
The only reason there weren't
any riots in the streets
when we fired on the Ganymede ships
was because they were Belters.
Sooner or later, an Earth ship
will try to run the blockade.
Are you going to shoot down
our own citizens,
or are we gonna turn this
situation to our advantage?
We are going to do what I goddamn said
we are going to do.
So do it.
Are you familiar
with the Barbapiccola?
Refugee ship from Ganymede.
One of the four that slipped
through the Ring
before the blockade went up.
They were never heard from again.
We heard from them again.
The Belters have been
installing comm relays
through the Ring gates,
prioritizing those four systems.
The relays went live two days ago
and started picking up
broadcasts from one system.
By some miracle, the Belters
on this world survived.
About a hundred or so.
They're calling the planet Ilus.
Makes sense.
Ilus was a brother of Ganymede.
Who gives a fuck?
I didn't bring you here
to teach me mythology.
The planet is practically
made of lithium.
They're mining it.
Belters struck it rich. Good for them.
They also found this.
That looks like the work
of the protomolecule.
Doesn't appear to be active.
And for a few hundred years,
we thought Phoebe was just
a ball of ice orbiting Saturn.
I want you to go to Ilus.
Are you still talking to Miller?
It's more like he talks to me.
You said the worlds on the other side
of those Rings were killed...
genocide on a scale
that we cannot even begin
to comprehend.
You have the insight
to the protomolecule
that no one else does.
I need to know what is really
going on over there.
Is Ilus a ghost town
or another fucking Eros?
And if it is another Eros?
Evacuate the Belters,
destroy the protomolecule if you can,
and get the hell out of there.
Nice of Avasarala to clear up
our salvage claim.
- How'd she look?
- Fine.
No, I mean, like,
what was she wearing?
It's good to be home.
Avasarala's worried it could
become another Eros.
If Miller's right, it could
be something much worse.
She already has a ship
en route, the Edward Israel.
It's a science ship,
survey vessel out of Titan.
- A warship's more her style.
- That's for sure.
It's not
a military operation.
They've got the gear
and the expertise to assess
the situation and hopefully
contain any contamination.
We'll have access to their
resources if we need them.
Look, I opened those gates.
So I'm responsible if
anything comes through them.
We all opened those gates.
All right.
At Ilus, Amos and I will
transfer to the Edward Israel
and take their shuttle
down to the surface.
Naomi, you and Alex will
stay in orbit on the Roci...
I'm going to the surface, too.
Are you sure?
It's a long trip to Ilus.
I'll have time to prepare.
There's 1,300 new systems out there,
and I don't want
to see them all from orbit.
All right, then, in which case,
we're gonna need to rig the Roci
for an unassisted landing.
- I know a guy on Luna.
- Give him a call.
So this guy
does MCRN retrofits?
Uh-huh, works cheap
and fast, doesn't ask questions.
Naomi...
Whatever happens down there,
we'll deal with it together.
Arriving
at Innis Shallows Station.
Stand clear of the doors.
Civilian
Accountability Committee
reminds all citizens that
your quarterly action report
is due in two weeks.
The assistance desk is open
for 24 hours and 2/3
for your questions and concerns.
Don't miss your deadline.
Mars is better for everyone
when everyone does their part.
Bobbie.
See you, Rana.
Hey, I got a few bites on apartments,
so I shouldn't be too much longer.
As long as you need, Bobbie.
I'm gonna shower
and head out for a pop.
Keep an eye out for David?
Sure.
Hey, sit down. Stay awhile.
Can't. Got a study date.
Huh. Pretty good. Thank you.
Yeah, I can really heat 'em up.
Shit, she's early.
Hey, Leelee.
Let me get my stuff.
Hey?
You're Aunt Bobbie.
David talks about you all the time.
He says you're a war hero.
He's a sweet kid.
Uh, you ready?
It's nice to meet you.
Hey, Bobbie.
Nice to see you, flyboy.
I'm just passing
through the neighborhood,
thought I'd check in live
for a change.
How you doing?
- Getting by.
- Oh, yeah?
I saw the news
you're heading to the Ring.
Are you going to New Terra?
I can neither confirm nor deny that.
There's protomolecule down there.
Yeah, so it would appear.
Apparently we are experts
in the field,
so who better to go
and see for sure, right?
And how are you feeling about it?
You wouldn't understand.
What's that supposed to mean?
You've never been scared
of anything in your life.
Sure, I have. All the time.
But there's a trick.
You just have to believe
that what you're doing really matters,
- and then the fear can't control you.
- Oh, shit. Delay's getting bad.
Shit.
Take care of yourself, flyboy.
You too, Bobbie.
UN freighter Amberjack,
we got you target lock.
Give us cargo.
We no fight and you live.
Answer now.
Unidentified pirata,
this is O.P.A.S. Tynan.
We have target lock.
Shut down your drive.
Prepare to be boarded.
Comply, or we will be forced to fire.
You rabbiting, bossmang.
Fo da shasa.
Ready the grapple.
Radiation spiking.
Evasive action!
They're dumping core!
What faction are you with?
It pay well?
Fo kill your own...
fo da Inners?
Three UN supply ships got hit
on this trade route in one month.
Who is ignoring the truce?
The one that still fight for the Belt.
Guess you the Inners'
good little koyo now.
Content for the table scraps.
They keep Belters out of the Ring
so they find the gold first,
leave us with dirt.
And you help them.
Good little koyo.
Rocinante, you are entering
the Ring Blockade Zone.
Please transmit your access code.
Roger that.
There you go, partner.
Code received and verified.
You're clear for transit.
It's nice to know Martians
have to go through this as well.
Yeah, but they get to train
for years in one G.
- How am I doing?
- Good.
Bone density, muscle mass,
heart-lung capacity all up.
They send a mining company
- under the name of science...
- You need a break?
...to steal our land,
the legitimate claim of our people.
They call Belters terrorists
to strip us of our rights.
We all lost family on Ganymede
because of the Inners' war.
- Yeah.
- Ilus is our home now,
and we will not be driven out again.
Yeah.
Keep going.
Hmm.
Oye, Nagata.
What are you doing here?
Is the universe about to end again?
Did you think I'd miss a chance
to talk to you in real time?
Good to see you, kopeng.
A bit of a surprise to be seen.
The Inners don't shoot us
to pieces with their railguns.
We don't nuke the Ring.
One big happy family now, I guess.
You've been busy, eh?
Over 40 Ring comm relays
installed to date, I gather.
Forty-two, which means only 1,331
to go.
With Medina Station the hub of it all.
It's a good command.
Only gas station on the new frontier.
We're putting in a souvenir shop.
Be a lot of business
after the blockade lifts.
- How is your back?
- Only hurts when I move.
Which means nerves are regrowing,
so that's good.
You're bound for Ilus.
That's right.
With James Holden on the gunship.
You're going to get
the Belters off that planet.
We're not going to evict anyone.
We're going to make sure it's safe.
Safe?
You hear how many of those refugees
died trying to adapt?
A lot of them had to go
back up to orbit.
They were foolish to think
they could live there.
It's not foolish to want free air
and free water
and a home for their children.
We are creatures of space.
In two generations,
their children will be Inners.
They won't even remember
what they were.
Everyone should have the right
to decide for themselves.
Of course.
Xalte to sif, Camina.
Dewe fasi, Nagata.
We won't be able to assess
how badly the Belters
have contaminated the atmosphere
until we've actually
been on the planet,
but once you're there,
I'm hoping we can
convince them of the need
to limit the damage.
I'm looking forward to working
with you, Captain.
We'll see you on New Terra.
We're through the Ring.
Be on Ilus in a few weeks. Then what?
I'll let you know.
Thanks for the ride.
What... what are we supposed... Wait!
Got something you want
to say to me, sailor?
Can I...
Can I buy you another beer?
Got RlF'd about
six months back.
They told our whole unit,
"Hey, thanks for the memories.
You're all civilians now."
Had a promotion coming up, too.
That's the shit end of the stick.
You should know.
I watched your hearing on the feed.
You could've saved
your benefits if you signed
that statement they were
waving in front of you.
I'm sure it was good entertainment.
- But you wouldn't.
- I stand by what I did,
and I can live with the fallout.
That's what a Marine does.
First they order you to lie.
Then they strip you of your pension,
your skin, when you put honor first.
And he doesn't bitch and whine
when the chips are down.
He goes to the VA,
gets a regular job...
I'm there every goddamn day
waiting in line.
The problem is, you've got
too much time to think.
It's making you crazy.
- Crazy?
- Yeah.
- Me crazy?
- Mmm-hmm.
You look like you're
about ready to vent
someone's skull for
looking at you the wrong way.
You're not exactly the
poster girl for mental health.
I didn't vent yours.
Oh, bleeding heart.
Let me ask you something.
You were inside that Ring station.
What did you see?
Nothing that would make sense,
except a bunch of people
killing each other
to control something
they didn't even understand.
Tell you what, sailor.
Hang on to that uniform.
Keep in tip-top.
You can be damn sure there are
plenty more wars coming.
Beltalowda would be wise to ask,
if now we kill our own
on order of the Inners,
is this peace worth the price?
The OPA does not speak for all.
And those who stand with Fred Johnson
and Anderson Dawes should bear in mind
the inevitable fate of
wellwalla and collaborators.
Tynan, you're entering
the Ring Blockade Zone.
Please transmit your access code.
Tynan, no entry
to the Ring is permitted
without proper authorization.
Transmit your access code immediately.
Bossmang, they target-lock us.
Tynan, this is
your final warning.
Ah, give it to them.
Code verified.
Tynan, you're cleared for the Ring.
- Ashford.
- What?
We have enough problems already
without you agitating the Inners.
Well, they like humiliating us.
It's bad enough I have to play
cop to protect their haulers.
- We have a treaty.
- Worth what to the Belt?
We'll find out, keya?
You have to trust your gut.
Well, the last time I did that,
it didn't work out so well, did it?
We were all flying blind, Pampaw.
Yeah, well, me more than you.
Only because my friend had a boyfriend
with an imaginary friend
who told us how to power
that station down.
And I thought
he was a madman.
But he... he turns out to be a prophet.
It's possible to be both.
Why'd I let you talk me into this?
Are you kidding?
First scientists ever
to study a whole new biome.
We're making history.
Maybe you will. This planet
has no geological activity.
And isn't that amazing?
I was with the Hygeia group
when we found some Belters
squatting on a rock
with a billion in platinum ore
- that we had the charter for.
- How'd that go?
We gave them a percentage
of the take, 300K,
topped off their water tanks,
sent them on their way.
You got off cheap.
Yeah, the company called it a win.
Well, let's hope it's that easy here.
Yeah, we've got a legal charter
from the UN and Mars, so...
You think the OPA
give a shit about that?
No, I do not.
Lighten up, Fayez.
You're about to be famous.
Bet the rocks down here look
just like the ones back home.
Well, I'll name a new bug
after you.
Hold tight!
There's one over here!
Give me the mask!
All right.
Twenty-three
of our people are dead,
including the mission commander
and the ship's physician.
The heavy lift shuttle was destroyed,
along with most
of the expedition's supplies.
Security Chief Murtry
refused evacuation
and is now in operational
command of the expedition.
Cause of the crash
is currently unknown.
The Belters are
providing what aid they can
but hasten to add
the company had no right
to land in the first place.
It could have been
an accident or attack
or something much worse.
The story is already
metastasizing on newsfeeds.
Just get yourself to Ilus,
do your job,
and let RCE do theirs.
The Belters will try
to enlist you to their cause.
Holden, do not put your dick in it.
It's fucked enough already.
It's good advice.
Cap, test fire lined up.
Fire at will.
Take that, blue goo.
Belte hero.
You na kang let them take us
from our land.
This our home.
This our land, huh? This Belter land.
Nobody's doing anything to anybody.
We're here to help.
Welcome. Carol Chiwewe.
I'm the administrator
of the settlement.
- Jim Holden.
- Captain Holden.
Chief Murtry. Welcome to New Terra.
Come with me.
I'll give you the lay of the land.
Good to meet you.
Hey, you here fo help us or help them?
All right, all right,
easy there, partner.
Traitors!
Traitor. Traitor.
Traitor!
Whoa, whoa!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Everybody put your guns down now!
- Amos, you, too.
- Him first.
You've got two seconds.
Pashang, you got one.
What the fuck is that?
Take cover!
You okay?
Amos.
Son of a bitch.
- Jesus.
- What the fuck was that?
Hey, you okay?